<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<wps:ProcessDescriptions xmlns:wps="http://www.opengis.net/wps/1.0.0" xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows/1.1" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.opengis.net/wps/1.0.0
http://schemas.opengis.net/wps/1.0.0/wpsDescribeProcess_response.xsd" xml:lang="en-US" service="WPS" version="1.0.0">
	<ProcessDescription wps:processVersion="2" statusSupported="true" storeSupported="true">
		<ows:Identifier>org.n52.wps.ags.analysis.overlay.union</ows:Identifier><!-- ParameterCount=5 -->		
		<ows:Title>Union_analysis</ows:Title>
		<ows:Abstract>Computes a geometric intersection of the Input Features. All features will be written to the Output Feature Class with the attributes from the Input Features, which it overlaps. Uses ArcObjects library - Analysis</ows:Abstract>
		<DataInputs>
			<Input minOccurs="1" maxOccurs="1000">
				<ows:Identifier>in_features</ows:Identifier><!-- 0 -->
				<ows:Title>in features</ows:Title>
				<ows:Abstract>A list of the input feature classes or layers. When the distance between features is less than the cluster tolerance, the features with the lower rank will snap to the feature with the higher rank. The highest rank is one. All the Input Features must be polygons. With ArcView and ArcEditor licenses, the number of input feature classes or layers is limited to two.</ows:Abstract>
				<ComplexData>
					<Default>
						<Format>
							<MimeType>application/x-zipped-shp</MimeType>
							<Schema></Schema>
						</Format>
					</Default>
					<Supported>
						<Format>
							<MimeType>application/x-zipped-shp</MimeType>
							<Schema></Schema>
						</Format>	
					</Supported>
				</ComplexData>
			</Input>
			<Input minOccurs="0" maxOccurs="1">
				<ows:Identifier>join_attributes</ows:Identifier><!-- 2 -->
				<ows:Title>join attributes</ows:Title>
				<ows:Abstract>Determines what attributes will be transferred to the Output Feature Class. ALL — All the attributes (including FIDs) from the Input Features as well as the Identity Features will be transferred to the Output Feature Class. This is the default. NO_FID — All the attributes except the FID from the Input Features and Identity Features will be transferred to the Output Feature Class. ONLY_FID — All the attributes from the Input Features but only the FID from the Identity Features will be transferred to the Output Feature Class.</ows:Abstract>
				<LiteralData>
					<ows:DataType ows:reference="xs:string"></ows:DataType>
					<ows:AllowedValues>
						<ows:Value>ALL</ows:Value>
						<ows:Value>NO_FID</ows:Value>
						<ows:Value>ONLY_FID</ows:Value>
					</ows:AllowedValues>	
				</LiteralData>
			</Input>
			<Input minOccurs="0" maxOccurs="1">
				<ows:Identifier>cluster_tolerance</ows:Identifier><!-- 3 -->
				<ows:Title>cluster tolerance</ows:Title>
				<ows:Abstract>The minimum distance separating all feature coordinates (nodes and vertices) as well as the distance a coordinate can move in X or Y (or both). You can set the value to be higher for data that has less coordinate accuracy and lower for datasets with extremely high accuracy.</ows:Abstract>
				<LiteralData>
					<ows:DataType ows:reference="xs:string"></ows:DataType>
					<ows:AnyValue/>
				</LiteralData>	
			</Input>
			<Input minOccurs="0" maxOccurs="1">
				<ows:Identifier>gaps</ows:Identifier><!-- 4 -->
				<ows:Title>gaps</ows:Title>
				<ows:Abstract>Gaps are areas in the output feature class that are completely enclosed by other polygons. This is not invalid, but it may be desirable to identify these for analysis. To find the gaps in the output, set this option to NO_GAPS, and a feature will be created in these areas. To select these features, query the output feature class based on all the input feature's FID values being equal to -1. GAPS — No feature will be created for areas in the output that are completely enclosed by polygons. This is the default. NO_GAPS — A feature will be created for the areas in the output that are completely enclosed by polygons. This feature will have blank attributes.
				</ows:Abstract>
				<LiteralData>
					<ows:DataType ows:reference="xs:boolean"></ows:DataType>
					<ows:AnyValue/>	
				</LiteralData>
			</Input>
		</DataInputs>
		<ProcessOutputs>
			<Output>
				<ows:Identifier>out_feature_class</ows:Identifier><!-- 2 -->
				<ows:Title>out feature class</ows:Title>	
				<ows:Abstract>The feature class that will contain the results.</ows:Abstract>
				<ComplexOutput>
					<Default>
						<Format>
							<MimeType>application/x-zipped-shp</MimeType>
							<Schema></Schema>
						</Format>
					</Default>
					<Supported>
						<Format>
							<MimeType>application/x-zipped-shp</MimeType>
							<Schema></Schema>
						</Format>	
						<Format>
					    <MimeType>text/XML</MimeType>
						  <Schema>http://schemas.opengis.net/gml/2.1.2/feature.xsd</Schema>
				    </Format>
					</Supported>
				</ComplexOutput>
			</Output>
		</ProcessOutputs>
	</ProcessDescription>
</wps:ProcessDescriptions>
									